Alchemy, the science of understanding,
deconstructing, and reconstructing matter.
However, it is not an all-powerful art.
It is impossible to create
something out of nothing.
If one wishes to obtain something,
something of equal value must be given.
This is the law of equivalent exchange,
the basis of all alchemy.
In accordance with this law,
there is a taboo among alchemists.
Human transmutation is strictly forbidden.
For what could equal the value
of a human soul?
Kono omoi wo keshite shimau niwa
mada jinsei nagai dsho?
Yarinokoshite'ru koto
yarinaoshite mitai kara
Yume no tsuzuki oikakete ita hazu na no ni
Magarikunetta
hosoi michi hito ni tsumazuku
Ano koro mitai ni tte modoritai wake ja nai ni
Nakushite kita sora wo sagashite'ru
Wakatte kuremasu you ni
Gisei ni natta you na
kanashii kao wa yamete yo
Tsumi no saigo wa namida ja nai yo
Zutto kurushiku seotte'ku n da
Deguchi mienai kanjou meiro ni
dare wo matte'ru no?
Shiroi nooto ni tsuzutta you ni
motto sunao ni hakidashitai yo
Nani kar nogaretai n da
genjitsu tte yatsu?
Kanaeru tame ni ikite'ru n datte
Sakebitaku naru yo Kikoete imasu ka?
Bunai n nante yatte'rarenai kara
...kaeru basho mo nai no
Yasashisa niwa itsumo kansha shite'ru
Dakara tsuyoku naritai
(I'm on the way)
Natsukashiku naru
konna itami mo kangei jan
Brother.
Hmm?
The stories about this priest in Liore...
You think they're true?
The ones about his "miracles"?
They say he can transmute flowers
out of thin air, right?
Could just be slight of hand,
some cheap trick like that.
But...what if it's not?
Right.
If it's not, then I suppose all
that leaves is the real thing, huh?
The celestial stone that destroyed
the city of Xerxes in one night,
the grand elixir sealed
away by the Eastern Sage.
It goes by different names,
but it's always the same thing,
some kind of object
that amplifies alchemy.
That's the Philosopher's Stone.
If we could just get our hands on it somehow,
I might be able to get your body back.
Damn books!
They tell us everything but how to find it!
Al?
Yeah?
I think I have a good
feeling about this one.
Mmm, me too.
Translation: Resembool, 10 years earlier
Ed? Al? Where are you?
Oh, you boys.
Are you in here messing
up your dad's study again?
And Ed, you know better
than to scribble on the floor.
Yeah, but it's not scribbling.
Here, watch!
Oh, my!
That's alchemy, isn't it?
Did your dad teach you that?
How can he teach us
anything if he's not here?
Right, we read about it in these books!
I can't believe you've done this.
I'm sorry, did we mess up?
No, no! It's great!
You definitely take after your father.
My little geniuses,
you make me so proud!
ED (Narrating): And that was it!
Mom had given us all the
encouragement we needed.
From that moment,
we were obsessed with learning alchemy.
But then, in the summer of that same year,
an epidemic swept the country.
The sickness came and it took her.
Hey, brother?
I'm hungry, aren't you?
And it's cold here.
Let's go home, please.
Once dad comes back, everything'll be—
Don't even talk about him!
That bastard doesn't care about us.
He's not our dad.
He didn't even come for Mom's funeral.
You know, there might be
a way we could bring Mom back.
But I thought it said in all the books that using alchemy to
make people is something you're not supposed to do, ever.
That's right.
That's why it'll be our secret.
I thought I'd find you here.
What do you want, Winry?
You know what my grandma says?
She says you shouldn't cry for
loved ones who've passed away.
Because when you do, it makes
them feel sad in the next world, too.
We're not crying!
And who are you to talk anyway?
Every time your parents go away somewhere,
you cry like a little baby!
I... I do not!
Are you sure, baby?
I'm so stupid for worrying about you!
I'm going home to tell Grandma
not to make you any dinner!
ED: Hey! What are you gonna do that for?!
ED: Hold up!
AL: Yeah, wait for us!
Thanks for dinner!
Come on, Ed. Drink your milk, too.
No, I hate milk.
If you don't drink it,
you'll stay short forever.
You mean like you,
you sawed-off old hag?
What was that,
you little half-pint midget?!
- Shrunk down, mini-witch!
- Micro pee-wee!
- Baby ant baby!
-Subatomic shrimp!
[SCHOOL BELLS RINGING]
WINRY: You're reading those weird
books in the middle of class again.
You need to pay attention to the lessons!
ED: Leave us alone, will ya?
WINRY: So, what kind of books are they anyway?
It's a secret.
In other words, it's none of
your damn business, Winry!
C'mon, no fair!
You guys are always keeping secrets.
[AL GIGGLES]
AL: Bye, Winry!
[GASP]
Hey!  I forgot!
Grandma wanted me to tell you
she's making stew tonight!
Yay, stew!
Right, we'll be there.
ED: Y'know, whoever invented stew
must have been a genius.
It's even got milk in it,
and it still tastes good.
So that makes it genius?
Someone came up with the idea to pour
milk into vegetable soup for the first time, right?
That's a leap of imagination!
The kind a scientist needs
to be able to make, too.
I don't know, I guess that's true.
Sure it is!
Just one leap, that's all it takes.
And it's what we need to
figure out human transmutation.
ED: And so we began searching for the key that would unlock
the secrets of human transmutation and bring mom back to life.
We trained with an alchemy teacher,
to prepare our bodies as well as our minds.
It took years of constant effort,
but we wanted to see mom smile again.
We wanted to go back to our lives with her
the way they used to be.
That's what drove us, day and night.
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
And we're ready.
[RAVEN CAWING]
Water 35 liters; carbon 20 kilograms;
ammonia, 4 liters; lime, 1.5 kilograms;
phosphorus, 800 grams; salt, 250 grams;
saltpeter, 100 grams; sulfur, 80 grams;
fluorine, 7.5 grams; iron 5 grams; silicon, 3 grams.
Right, now the construction formula.
And finally, we need some soul data.
- Okay, this is it, Al.
- Mmm.
Ed, something doesn't feel right.
[AL SCREAMS]
ED: Al!
No!
It can't be... a rebound?
Brother!
Ed! Help...! Ed...!
- Brother!
- Al!
Al?
Wait. What was I doing?
I just...
Hello.
Who are you?
Oh! I'm so glad you asked.
I am called by names.
I am the world, I am the universe,
I am God, I am truth,
I am all, I am one, and I am also...
You.
[GASP]
You have dared to knock on the door.
Now the door is open.
[ED SCREAMING]
Quiet, child.
This is what you wanted, isn't it?
[SCREAM]
I will show you the truth!
It was like all of the information in the world
was being poured into my brain at once.
It's too much!
It's too much, make it stop!
What's happening to me?!
Stop it! Make it stop!
Make it stop!
[GASPS]
My head felt like it was about to burst.
But for instant, it all became clear.
The truth of everything.
Mom... mom please!
How was it?
I see... My theory of human
transmutation wasn't wrong.
It can be done. It's possible!
It's still just missing something!
All of the answers I need are right here.
The truth about human transmutation!
Please, you have to show it to me again!
I can't do that.
I've already shown you
all I can for the toll you've paid.
Toll? What toll?
This...
Surely you knew.
It's the law of equivalent exchange.
Right, young alchemist?
[SCREAMS]
Dammit. This can't be happening!
It can't be... This wasn't...
This wasn't supposed to... NO!
He's gone, what I have done?!
Somebody help me. Somebody...
Please, Mom... Mom, please.
[GASP]
[CHOKED, GASPING BREATHS]
No... this... this is wrong.
This isn't..
This isn't what we wanted!
[CRYING] Al... Alphonse... Alphonse!
Alphonse!
This is all my fault...
Alphonse, no...!
No, dammit!
You won't take him too!
Give him back! He's my brother...
Take my leg! Take my arm!
Take my heart! Anything, you can have it!
Just give him back!
He's my little brother,
he's all I have left!
Fullmetal Alchemist.
HUGHES: Roy! Hey, you're still in Central?
For now anyway. They're shipping me back
to Eastern Command this afternoon.
Well, now aren't you the lucky one.
Next time you come here, I expect you to
have made Brigadier General.
You got that? Heh, heh.
Easy for you to say.
[HUGHES LAUGHS]
Oh, by the way, if you're leaving,
I'll go ahead and give this to you.
What is it?
Something you might find interesting, the final report on Isaac McDougal.
I'm guessing it hasn't reached your office yet.
No.
Xingese alkahestry, what's that?
Apparently, that's something they have
to be honest, no idea. You don't know it?
No, it's the first I've heard of it.
So, how're the Elrics doing?
You keeping those boys out of trouble?
I'm their commanding officer,
not their father.
Hmm.
Hey, tell me something, Roy,
why'd you decide to make Ed
a State Alchemist anyway?
He's just a kid.
I mean, military life isn't easy, you know.
That boy's gonna have to go through hell someday.
You and I have certainly seen our share.
ROY: Hell, huh?
Oh, they've seen hell.
Both of them. And plenty of it.
Translation: "4 years earlier"
Lieutenant Colonel,
they're not in back either...
What is this?
Where are they?
Where are they? Where are the
Elric Brothers? I want them found!
[DOG BARKING]
Oh, hush, Den,
don't bark at our guest.
Yes?
Hey, what is this?!
You have no reason to come barging in here!
We went to your house, we saw the floor.
What was that?
What did you do?
We're sorry. We didn't mean it.
We're sorry. We're sorry. We're sorry.
[AL'S ARMOR TREMBLING]
Wait, are you...?
MUSTANG: This is a surprise to say the least.
I'd heard reports that there was a brilliant alchemist
living in this town, so I came to check them out.
The last thing I expected to find was a boy skilled enough to attempt human transmutation.
Or advanced enough to bond a soul to a suit of armor.
I'd say he's more than qualified
to become a State Alchemist.
Should he choose to accept the position,
he'll be required to serve the military
in times of national emergency.
In return, he'll receive privileges and access
to otherwise restricted research materials.
Given time, they may be able to find
a way to get their bodies back, or even more.
Right after he came stumbling to my door,
half dead and covered in blood,
I went over to their house to
see for myself what had happened.
What was there...
Whatever that thing was,
it wasn't human!
Alchemy created that abomination,
it nearly killed them,
And you want to throw those
boys headlong into it?
Would you really have them go
through that kind of hell again?
WINRY: Some tea?
Yes, thanks.
Say, uh... Lieutenant?
Just Riza, please. It's Riza Hawkeye.
Nice to meet you.
Lieutenant Riza, have you
ever had to shoot anyone?
Yes, I have.
I hate what you soldiers do.
Soldiers like you are the reason my mom and dad left
during the war, and soldiers are the reason they're dead.
And now you...
Now you're here to take Ed and Al away, too.
If they go, that decision will be theirs,
and theirs alone.
Yes. It's entirely up to them now.
MUSTANG: I'm not forcing you.
I'm merely offering you the possibility.
Whether to move forward or stay still.
Will you sit in that chair, wallowing in self-pity?
Or will you stand up and seize the chance the military can give you?
It's their choice.
They choose their own path.
If you believe the possibility exists for getting your bodies back
you should seek it out, keep moving, whatever it takes.
Even if the way ahead
lies through a river of mud.
Miss Riza, why did you become a soldier?
[SOFT CHUCKLE]
Because there's someone I have to protect.
We're leaving.
Yes, so.
HAWKEYE: Well, I guess this is goodbye, young lady.
It's Winry.
Right. Bye, Winry.
I hope we meet again someday.
HAWKEYE: Will they be coming?
MUSTANG: They'll come.
HAWKEYE: That boy...I've never
seen anyone look so defeated.
That's what you saw?
No. There was fire in those eyes.
PINAKO: You sure you won't regret this?
ED: Hmm. My mind's made up.
How long will the surgery
and rehabilitation take?
I'd say about three years, more or less.
I'll do it in one.
[BOTH GASP]
You'll have yourself spitting blood,
you know that?
Al?
Just hang in there a little longer, okay?
Then we're gonna get you
your body back, I promise.
Right. And while we're at it,
we'll get yours back, too.
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
Seems like you're in perfect shape!
Yeah, now I just need to try some alchemy.
I guess it's been a while
since the last time I used it.
I know. Not since the night we
tried to bring mom back, right?
Brother!
Yeah, I'd say that's right on the money—
No, it's amazing!
You didn't even use a transmutation circle!
You perform alchemy
the same way that teacher does!
You can do it, too, can't you?
Me? No. No way!
So you didn't see it, did you?
See what?
Uh...never mind.
[CRASH]
Hey, you! Don't mess up my auto mail!
You know how hard I worked on that?!
Hell, if it's half as you throw
a wrench I'd be surprised!
[GROANS]
For real... you could try acting more
like a girl and less like a gearhead.
You think I'm a gearhead? That's fine, but you had better get used to it!
'Cause as long as you're wearing my automail,
you're stuck with this gearhead, whether you like it or not!
Huh?
It's unusual for you to
observe the examination, sir.
That's true, but I hear we have
a twelve-year-old boy taking the test.
Thought I would come out and see
what all the excitement was about.
Ah, would that be a steel prosthetic?
Happened during the Eastern conflict.
I see. So you had a rough
time of it in Ishval, hmm?
Who's he?
You idiot! That's his excellency,
Führer King Bradley!
Hmm.
Thank you.
You may proceed with the examination.
Do you need something to
draw transmutation circles with?
No, that's okay. I got it.
He's not even using a transmutation circle!
My, that's quite something, isn't it?
Führer!
You know, there are some people who would see
this as a good way to assassinate a VIP.
In the future, you might wanna rethink
the way you conduct these examinations.
Hmm!
That's good! You clearly
have nerves of steel, young man.
But... I'd say you still have
much to learn about the world.
Hmm?
Ah!
[CHUCKLING] You put a quite a show,
my naive young alchemist.
Good luck with the rest of your exams.
When did he draw his sword?
AL: I wonder if Ed's doing
all right on his exam.
Say, Al?
Yeah? What is it?
If Ed does become a State Alchemist...
does that mean you'll be going away?
Yeah.
MUSTANG: This silver pocket watch will serve
as proof of your state certification.
This envelope contains your certificate of appointments.
(Translation: "East City, Eastern Command Center")
Heh...
And it would seem our Fuhrer
is not without a certain sense of irony.
Why is that?
Nothing. Congratulations.
You've just officially
become a dog of the military.
By order of Fuhrer King Bradley,
this document certifies that Edward Elric
has been appointed to
the post of state alchemist,
and that he is hereby
granted the title of Fullmetal.
Fullmetal?
That's right.
Along with their commission,
State Alchemists also receive a codename.
Officially, you will now be known as...
The Fullmetal Alchemist.
I like that. It's nice and intimidating.
I think that'll suit me just fine.
AL: Hey, wake up...we're almost there!
ED: So that's Liore?
Could it really be there? The key to
finally getting Al his body back?
The Philosopher's Stone!
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora o
nee kimi wa oboete imasu ka
Yakusoku chigiri shoka
no kaze ga tsutsumu
futari yorisotta
Muri na egao no ura
nobita kage o kakumau
Dakara kizukanu furi saisei o erabu
Table no ue no furuenai shirase machitsuzukete
kuuhaku no yoru o kuru hazu no nai asa mo
zenbu wakatte'tan da
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora o
nee itsuka omoidasu deshou
Hatasenakatta yakusoku o idaite
futari arukidasu
Having arrived in Liore, Ed and Al encounter Father Cornello,
a priest who claims he can perform miracles.
Blinded by false promises of eternal
life and resurrection for the dead,
Cornello's followers fail to see the blood red stone
that gleams on his finger, or realise what it means.
Next time on Fullmetal Alchemist: Brotherhood
Episode 3: City of Heresy
What happiness can possibly be gained
by looking away from the truth?